Can you find the wolves in this picture?
Killers of the Flower Moon is a crime, history,
drama film directed by Martin Scorsese.
When oil is discovered in 1920s Oklahoma under Osage Nation land, the Osage people
are murdered one by one—until the FBI steps in to unravel the mystery.
Ernest Burkhart, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
William Hale, played by Robert De Niro.
Mollie Burkhart, played by Lily Gladstone.
Tom White, played by Jesse Plemons.
Lizzie Q, played by Tantoo Cardinal.
Prosecutor Peter Leaward, played by John Lithgow.
Killers of the Flower Moon is a 2023 American epic anti-Western crime drama film directed by Martin
Scorsese, who co-wrote the screenplay with Eric Roth, based on the 2017 nonfiction book.
It stars Leonardo DiCaprio, Robert De Niro, and Lily Gladstone.
Set in 1920s Oklahoma, it focuses on a series of murders of Osage members and
relations in the Osage Nation after oil was discovered on tribal land.
The tribal members had retained mineral rights on their reservation, but a
corrupt local political boss sought to steal the wealth.
It is the sixth feature film collaboration between Scorsese and DiCaprio, the tenth between Scorsese and De Niro, and the eleventh and final
between Scorsese and composer Robbie Robertson, who died two months before the film's release and to whom the film is dedicated.
Development began in March 2016 when Imperative
Entertainment won the adaptation rights to the book.
Scorsese and DiCaprio were attached to the film in 2017, with
production expected to begin in early 2018.
Following several pushbacks and delays due to the COVID-19 pandemic, production was scheduled to start in February
2021, with Apple Studios confirmed to finance and distribute the film alongside Paramount Pictures.
Principal photography ultimately took place between April and
October 2021 in Osage and Washington counties, Oklahoma.
With its $200–215 million budget, it was reportedly the largest
amount ever spent on a film shoot in Oklahoma.
Killers of the Flower Moon premiered at the 76th
Cannes Film Festival on May 20, 2023.
It was theatrically released in the United States on October 20, by
Paramount Pictures, before streaming on Apple TV+ in January 2024.
The film grossed $158 million and received critical acclaim.
It won Best Film at the National Board of Review and was named one of
the top-ten films of 2023 by the American Film Institute.
It was also nominated for ten Academy Awards (including Best Picture), seven Golden Globe Awards (including Best
Motion Picture), nine British Academy Film Awards (including Best Film), and three SAG Awards.
For her performance, Gladstone won the Golden Globe and Screen Actors Guild Award for Best
Actress, and she received a nomination for the Academy Award for Best Actress.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based
on novel or book, war veteran, fbi, greed.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.